Preliminary Inventory to the William Sidney Graves Papers, 1914-1932
Hoover Institution Archives
William Sidney Graves Papers,
1914-1932
60009
Graves, William Sidney, 1865-1940
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, reports, monographs, and photographs, relating to the Allied intervention in Siberia, 1918-1919.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
United States. Army--Officers.; United States. Army. American Expeditionary Forces.; Siberia (Russia)--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--History--Allied intervention, 1918-1920.; United States--Armed Forces.
Container List
- General Graves' Personal Communications except his reports to the Adjutant General on the Siberian Situation
  - From Sept. 1, to October 31, 1918. Items 1-27 (Table of Contents). (Box 1, Folder G. W. 1)
  - From November 1, to Dec. 31, 1918. Items 28-49 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 2)
  - From Jan. 1, to Feb. 28, 1919. Items 50-80 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 3)
  - From March 1, to April 30, 1919. Items 81-116 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 4)
  - From May 1, to June 30, 1919. Items 117-156 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 5)
  - From July 1, to August 31, 1919. Items 157-158 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 6)
  - From Sept. 1 to October 31, 1919. Items 159-174 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 7)
  - From Nov. 1, to Dec. 31, 1919. Items 175-191 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 8)
- Various letters received by General Graves and copies of reports prepared by him. Items numbered 192-218 plus two items not numbered. (T.o.C.) (Folder G. W. 9)
- General Graves' Personal File of Cables to AGWAR
  - From Aug. 1918 to July 31, 1919. Items 1-82 (T.o.C.). (Box 2, Folder G. W. 10)
  - General Graves' Personal File of Cables to AGWAR; from Aug. 1, 1919 to Jan. 31, 1920. Items 83-184 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 11)
- Reports to the Adjutant General of the Army
  - From October 5, 1918 to November 5, 1919. Items 1-24 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 12)
- General Orders; 1918
  - Sept. 19, to December 26, 1918. Nos. 23-2 to 35 (t.o.C.) (Folder G. W. 13)
- General Orders; 1919
  - Feb. 22, 1919 to Dec. 4, 1919. Nos. 1-33 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 14)
- General Orders; 1920
  - Jan. 12, 1920. No. 1. (Folder G. W. 15)
- Memorandums; 1918
  - August 21, to Dec. 30, 1918. Nos. 1-61 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 16)
- Memorandums; 1919
  - Jan. 4 to December 30, 1919. Nos. 1-96 (T.o.C.). (Folder G. W. 17)
- Bulletins; 1918
  - Sept. 16 to Dec. 30, 1918. Nos. 1-25 (T.o.C.). (Box 3, Folder G. W. 18)
- Bulletin; 1919
  - Jan. 3, to June 26, 1919. Nos. 1-8 (T.o.C. incomplete). (Folder G. W. 19)
- An Account of the American Expeditionary Forces in Siberia. August 1918 to March 1919. Prepared in the Office of the Chief of Staff, American Expeditionary Forces, Siberia. April 1919. From the Official Records. By Laurence B. Packard, Captain, USA. At head of title page: CONFIDENTIAL., Typewritten, 118 pages; 3 maps. (Folder G. W. 20)
- Report of Operations of Engineer Detachment A.E.F.S.; from January 1, 1919 to June 30, 1919., Typewritten, 5 pages, 5 maps. (Folder G. W. 21)
- Earle W. Jennings, Major, Corps of Engineers; Chief Engineer Officer, American Expeditionary Forces, Siberia; Report on the Land Defenses of Vladivostok, Siberia. (No dates.), Typewritten, 14 pages; one map; numerous photographs. (Folder G. W. 22)
- Report of the Operations of the Medical Department from Beginning of the A.E.F. -S. to June 30, 1919. (Submitted by James S. Wilson, Colonel, Medical Corps, USA., Typewritten, 59 pages. (No date.) (Folder G. W. 23)
- The Czechoslovaks in Russia. August 1914 to February 1919. Prepared in the Office of the Chief of Staff, American Expeditionary Forces, Siberia; by Laurence B. Packard, Captain, USA. April 15, 1919. At head of title page: CONFIDENTIAL., Typewritten; 114 pages. (Folder G. W. 24)
- Military Monograph on Siberia containing information and Route Notes; From Vladivostok to Irkutsk. Volume 2, containing the illustrations to this Monograph. Bound volume, not paginated. (Folder G. W. 25)
- Mintz, I.: The United States in Intervention; a translation of the Introduction to the Russian edition of General Graves' America's Siberian Adventure, published in Moscow, 1932., (Typewritten, 27 pages) (pages 19-21 missing). (Folder G. W. 26)
- Folder containing 20 photographs of leading American and Japanese officers from the Command of both Intervention Armies. (Folder G. W. 27)
- Temporary Folder. Contains loose papers found in the box received from Mrs. W. R. Orton. These are documents which partially should be added to preceding folders and the remainder should be organized. This should be done before the collection is made available to scholars for use. (Folder G. W. 28)